BACKEND SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nahuel Brandán

contact@nahuelbrandan.com | mahuelbrandan.com/en | in





O Cba - Arg

ABOUT ME -

Computer Analyst / Backend Software Developer, specialized in Python, with 3+ years of experience, including recent work in the aerospace industry. Utilize skills and knowledge in the development of efficient and high-quality solutions. Actively strive to enhance technical documentation and implement optimal development practices to ensure the reliability and scalability of the work. Always in constant learning.

EXPERIENCE -

Company: <u>Satellogic</u> | Backend Developer

06/2022 - 09/2022

Satellogic is a company specialized in earth observation satellites.

- Refactored an application into two separate entities, reducing coupling and improving maintainability.
- Contributed to improve code quality through regular code reviews and technical discussions.

Company: Ascentio | Project: Sabia-Mar | Backend Developer 08/2021 - 05/2022 Sabia-Mar is a satellite mission, with advanced technology for the study of the sea and the ocean.

- Developed contributions to satellite flight planning and communication modules, using technologies such as: Python, Docker, FastAPI and APIs.
- Created unit and integration tests, using tools like Robot Framework, Postman and Pytest.

Company: IncluIT Project: Junar **Backend Developer** 03/2019 - 07/2021

- · Developed and maintained the backend base code of the system, based on Python, Django, and DRF.
- Integrated Auth0 and Keycloak technologies as security layers in API management.
- Executed an upgrade of Django versions and others +15 dependencies, to reduce the technical debt.
- Optimized 30% performance in response time of the APIs, through cache management.
- Managed technical onboarding to +10 new developers, providing guidance and technical support.

EDUCATION –

B.S in Computer Science - (Graduated) | Academy: FaMAF - UNC

10/2018

Career with strong emphasis on programming, analysis and design of systems, databases and computer networks, combining a solid theoretical understanding with practical skills.

COURSES -

Self-study online courses | Academy: Platzi

01/2021 - Present

Complete more than 100 courses completed and in constant learning in the professional online academy called Platzi, on topics such as: soft skills, English, software development.

SKILLS -

- · Programming languages: Python, C.
- Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Redis, Elasticsearch.
- Frameworks: Django, Django REST Framework, FastAPI, Robot Framework.
- Dev tools: Linux, REST API, Git, GitHub, Bash, Postman, Auth0, Docker, Celery.

LANGUAGES

- English: B1 intermediate.
- Spanish: Native.